[Music]
welcome to this session where we talk
about what's new with AI in business
Central now in March 2023 we introduced
you to Dynamics 365 co-pilot the world's
first AI powered assistant across Erp
and CRM and in business Central co-pilot
had just one skill initially marketing
Tech suggestions which gives our
customers that boost of creativity so
that they can draft uh product
descriptions and help them bring their
products to Market even
quicker now throughout the preview of
marketing Tech suggestions we've
received some incredibly encouraging and
positive feedback uh on this feature and
its capabilities and uh we got that from
our Partners we got it from our
customers and also from our focused user
studies and it's quite amazing to see
how AI really has that power to uh
surprise and Delight when it's put to
work in a business context uh and helps
our customers be dramatically more
productive so we're pleased to announce
that with 2023 release Wave 2 marketing
Tech suggestions is no longer in preview
it is now generally available my name is
mik B Cardona I'm a product manager at
Microsoft and together with me today is
Sam Hi Sam hi yeah I'm Sam van leart I'm
software engineer on the the business
Central team um so yes go through the
the agenda for today uh so top of the
list of course is uh that yeah marketing
Tech suggestions are GA so we'll we'll
cover what kind of what's what's new uh
with the ga changes coming from preview
and uh we'll give it a bit a go as well
um and lastly we'll go through
everything uh you need to know to to uh
get started and try it out yourself all
right so here we're in uh business
Central on the familiar role Center and
uh whether you're a partner showing a
demo to a prospect or you are an end
user just getting started with business
Central we have the welcome Banner here
and uh we make it super easy to demo the
uh the co-pilot functionality so you can
go ahead and see the demo tours and then
you'll see these uh checklists here and
you can skip right ahead to number five
and that's create with co-pilot and um
you can start the tour and this will
then show the tour
um for um the marketing text
suggestions and as you can see it allows
you to stop typing and start selling uh
the idea being that we take the item
attributes uh from the item and we'll
generate a product description um that
you can use along alongside uh your say
your web shop in
Shopify so I'll go and say next and then
it points out to the fact Blox control
here um which is where you will go ahead
and uh draft your uh marketing text with
the
copilot so um coming from preview
straight away you'll see that this uh
there's no reference to preview text
anymore in the fact box um that's not
the only thing we changed uh so if you
go ahead and click draft with co-pilot
now you'll see the uh The Familiar uh UI
that you can come to expect with
co-pilot experiences across all of the
Microsoft products uh so so yeah you can
see that we have generated uh some
marketing text just with one click using
all the item attributes in in in this uh
item um and um you know maybe I don't
like that it has included the uh the
width and depth uh of the uh the desk so
you can actually go ahead and uh edit
the prompt and here you can select the
the item attributes that you want to
include uh in the the marketing text
suggestion so I can go and uncheck the
depth height and width um as well we
made the uh the tone format and emphasis
more discoverable so I can actually say
you know sustainability is super
important so that's something I would
like to highlight um I think the tagline
and paragraph is pretty good I I like
that and the tone you know I uh I think
you know we want to be inspirational
with our products in this uh in this
company so so that's that's good then I
can go ahead and click generate and this
will generate a new suggestion uh it
will it will um keep the old one so if
if actually I preferred the previous one
I can go back
and I can see the original one uh but
let's let's take a look at this this new
one here so here you can see that here
we uh you know there's this greater
emphasis on
sustainability um so you know it's uh
and there's no mention to the the
dimensions of the products so I can
either choose now to to keep it and that
will actually then save this text to the
database or I can uh discard it if I if
I don't like it or I can even regenerate
and that will create a new a new
suggestion with the same par parameters
that I'd previously clicked uh but this
one's great so I'll go ahead and give it
a like so uh uh we can send that
feedback back and uh and I'll keep it so
uh another thing that I've revamped is
the the edit dialogue um so here again
we just focus on the the marketing text
uh that you already have uh in the
product and you can go ahead and and
edit this uh without the help of
co-pilot uh but if you would like to
draft some new text with co-pilot you
can go ahead and click this action and
because I already have text it warns me
it will replace it uh and I can go ahead
and select the specific attributes I
would like and uh of course I can I can
then just generate new uh marketing text
suggestions Sam if I may I love how
Snappy this feels uh it's got a really
fantastic beautiful experience here uh
you know as you work with co-pilot uh
even just a small details like down to
uh you know when it's showing you that
co-pilot is thinking is generating that
text those subtle details really make a
difference here and you know this is the
kind of thing which you really have to
get handson to really appreciate as well
uh and if you're a partner if you're not
showing this to your customers I think
you're really missing out on giving that
wow experience in business Central with
with co-pilot and these AI powered
experiences yeah so uh just to quickly
recap on on what you saw here so uh as
part of the marketing Tech suggestions
for ga uh we are now using the signature
co-pilot look and feel that you see
across all the product
uh We've improved the access to all the
different generative options within the
dialogue uh you don't no longer need to
click additional actions to make things
visible and that kind of thing and we've
really focused on depending at what
stage of uh generating your marketing
text uh' optimized the workspace
available to you so that you can focus
on that so Mike for co-prod features can
you tell us what does GA mean right
let's talk about availability let's dig
into some of the details here which are
so important for for you to understand
how to plan your approach so first of
all um marketing text suggestions and in
fact all of our co-pilot capabilities
going forward are only available for
business Central online what we also
refer to sometimes as
SAS um when will marketing Tech
suggestions get updated well the update
to marketing Tech suggestions will be
delivered in a minor update in wave two
now just as a reminder wave two minor
updates span from November till March 24
uh so what that means is that if you're
on update
23.0 uh you will still see the preview
experience of marketing Tech suggestions
you just have to wait for that minor
update now the feature is not restricted
by geography um which means that it's
available no matter which country
localization you use for your
environment um that's one of the
questions we get pretty often actually
and another one we get often is what
languages is this available in uh so
finally along with English we're also
expanding to seven more more languages
in which this feature is available uh
that includes Spanish Dutch German
Italian French Danish and Japanese now
this also includes localized variants of
those languages uh so we already know
this covers quite the bread of our uh
customer
population um and this also means that
if your environment is localized to for
example Sweden uh and your your users
can still switch to English to use the
feature in English and generate English
marketing text now many have asked you
know why in preview was this only
available in English uh and when are all
the other languages going to be
available it's a good question so I'd
like to clarify that um due to the very
nature of AI uh before we claim that any
AI powered feature is supported in so
and so languages what we do is we go
through quite an extensive assessment
process where we we verify the output of
AI uh against various criteria um and
the good news is we're already hard at
work with verifying the next batch of
languages which we will announce later
on for this particular
feature now as we unlock AI features in
more languages uh we really appreciate
your feedback on the quality of that
generated text so we know that AI can
produce engaging and surprisingly high
quality U text but we also know AI
doesn't always get it right so we've
provided a really simple way for you to
signal and rate that feedback right in
the UI alongside every single uh
generated text and you can do that every
time something is generated you can send
us your likes or dislikes along with the
reason uh and either way that really
helps us continue improving business
Central well next how about we take a
look Sam at uh you know how can you get
access to this where will you find it
what do you need to set up to to start
using marketing suggestions yeah yeah
yeah can do uh so there's there's a few
toggles that actually control the the
functionality of uh marketing text and a
few different aspects of it so uh I
think it' be a good idea to to walk
through them to help manage the the
actual UI impact of the marketing text
text functionality uh we have a feature
key in the feature management page um
that controls the uh availability of
like the factbox part and other uh UI
aspects of the marketing text feature
this does not manage like the the
generative AI aspects of uh marketing
text the marketing text suggestion it's
purely uh the UI for the marketing
text um this is enabled by default for
environments that have been created
since uh 2023 release Wave 1 so you
might know that as version 22 or above
um and uh another thing uh to make note
of is uh to determine whether or not the
ga capabilities have been enabled in
your environment and you can see that
just at a glance by checking the factbox
part here and if there's no mention to
preview here that means you've got the
ga bits so that's
good if you're upgrading from an earlier
version uh you'll need to go to the
feature management page as I said uh and
find this specific feature key which is
uh create AI powered product
descriptions with co-pilot and go and
enable that for for all users and then
uh next time users sign in uh they'll
they'll see the the marketing text
functionality on the
page now for the fun bit and enabling
the generative capabilities of marketing
text
um there's a another um toggle you'll
need to switch in the co-pilot and AI
capabilities page which is uh available
only in business Central online uh and
it's a new page that's kind of replacing
the the co-pilot information page that
we had in preview so this is enabled by
default but you need to keep in mind
that the the user language also needs to
support be supported for the generative
uh capabilities to show up lastly
there's uh one other toggle that you
might need to to click uh which is to
allow data movement if there's no AI
availability in your region uh if there
is AI availability in your region um you
don't need to consent to any data
movement but uh yeah if there's no
availability you you'll need to consent
to that movement uh by default uh this
is off uh so admins will go need to go
in and enable this um if you've used the
marketing text suggestions in preview it
should already be enabled so if you're
already using the feature there's no
action required here
um we're working very hard of course to
add this AI availability to more regions
so uh hopefully this additional setup
step uh will will go away in the future
uh back to you Mike thanks Sam well
let's before we close let's very quickly
just summarize uh so co-pilot in
business Central uh includes marketing
Tech suggestions and AI powered
capability that's now generally
available uh you'll find it in a minor
update to 2023 release Wave 2 um it's
available in eight languages and there's
no rest restrictions on Country
localization of your environment and if
you don't see marketing t uh Tech
suggestions show up uh there's probably
some onetime setup that you need to go
through um and of course do remember to
provide us feedback on that output of
generated
text now if you're a partner watching
this you're probably wondering how did
they do that uh well we have some good
news for you uh marketing Tech
suggestions has been rebuilt on our new
developer tools for co-pilot in business
Central uh which means that you can now
design and Implement very similar
generative AI experiences for your own
extensions um we have a dedicated
session for this really highly recommend
you watch that uh if you're looking for
more inspiration we've got a second
capability in the Box uh bank account
reconciliation assistance with co-pilot
go take a look at that one too and if
you missed a buzz last wave around
marketing Tech suggestions uh here's a
link to uh a video where we sort of
announced marketing Tech suggestions and
explain some of the details around uh
you know more technical details about
how suggestions work and how they're
generated but also how this is built on
the co-pilot system our Microsoft's
comprehensive approach to privacy
security compliance and responsible
AI there's plenty more resources if
you're looking to get started with
business Central uh follow the buzz on
social media or engage with the product
team people like ourselves and if you've
got that great idea for AI powered
capabilities that we should go and
Implement in business Central uh you
should share your ideas on aka.ms BC
ideas and if you're a partner we highly
recommend you join the discussion group
specifically about co-pilot and AI uh
you'll find the link right
here so it's been a real pleasure to
share with you how our first co-pilot
capability marketing Tech suggestions is
shaping up uh with marketing Tech
suggestions generally available uh we're
looking forward to hearing your feedback
uh on how we can evolve this further uh
we also hope this inspires you to see a
toward towards build building your own
AI powered capabilities in business
Central as well so on behalf of the
business Central team thanks for
watching thank
you